{
    "id": "11128eee34474cdd89846c4e263cd18a",
    "title": "Figures Of Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The righteous shall flourish as the palm tree.",
            "description": "A simile is usually introduced by such words as like, as or so.",
            "answers": [
                "simile",
                "metaphor",
                "personification"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Life is as tedious as a twice-told tale.",
            "description": "A simile is usually introduced by such words as like, as or so.",
            "answers": [
                "Simile",
                "Metaphor",
                "Hyperbole"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The camel is the ship of the desert.",
            "description": "A metaphor is an implied simile. It does not state that one thing is like another. Rather it takes that as granted and proceeds as if the two were one.",
            "answers": [
                "Simile",
                "Metaphor",
                "Oxymoron"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Variety is the spice of life.",
            "description": "A metaphor is an implied simile. It does not state that one thing is like another. Rather it takes that as granted and proceeds as if the two were one.",
            "answers": [
                "Simile",
                "Personification",
                "Metaphor"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Pride goeth forth on horseback, grand and gay.",
            "description": "In personification, inanimate objects and ideas are spoken of as having life and intelligence.",
            "answers": [
                "Oxymoron",
                "Apostrophe",
                "Personification"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "O Solitude! Where are the charms that sages have seen in thy face?",
            "description": "An apostrophe is a direct address to a personified object or idea.",
            "answers": [
                "Personification",
                "Hyperbole",
                "Apostrophe"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Death lays his icy hands on kings.",
            "description": "In personification, inanimate objects and ideas are spoken of as having life and intelligence.",
            "answers": [
                "Epigram",
                "Apostrophe",
                "Personification"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Why, man, if the river were dry, I am able to fill it with tears.",
            "description": "A hyperbole is statement made emphatic by overstatement.",
            "answers": [
                "Apostrophe",
                "Metaphor",
                "Hyperbole"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "O Hamlet! Thou hast cleft my heart in twain.",
            "description": "A hyperbole is statement made emphatic by overstatement.",
            "answers": [
                "Metaphor",
                "Oxymoron",
                "Hyperbole"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Man proposes, God disposes.",
            "description": "In antithesis a striking contrast of words or ideas are expressed in the same sentence.",
            "answers": [
                "Antithesis",
                "Hyperbole",
                "Oxymoron"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Many are called, but few are chosen.",
            "description": "In antithesis a striking contrast of words or ideas are expressed in the same sentence.",
            "answers": [
                "Antithesis",
                "Apostrophe",
                "Personification"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Here is the smell of blood still all the perfumes of Arabia will not sweeten this little hand.",
            "description": "A hyperbole is statement made emphatic by overstatement.",
            "answers": [
                "Euphemism",
                "Oxymoron",
                "Hyperbole"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}